const arr = [{"id":0,"info":"4th-year/reproductive/2017","question":"Which of the following factors is not associated with cervical carcinoma?","answers":[{"option":"Genetics","bool":false},{"option":"Age","bool":false},{"option":"Progesterone","bool":false},{"option":"Infection","bool":false},{"option":"Androgens","bool":true}]},{"id":1,"info":"4th-year/reproductive/2017","question":"Which gene is mutated in 90% of serous endometrial carcinomas?","answers":[{"option":"MED12","bool":false},{"option":"TP53","bool":true},{"option":"PTEN","bool":false},{"option":"PIK3CA","bool":false},{"option":"JAZF1","bool":false}]},{"id":2,"info":"4th-year/reproductive/2017","question":"What is the most common form of estrogen in combined oral contraceptive pills?","answers":[{"option":"Esterone sulfate","bool":false},{"option":"Estradiol","bool":false},{"option":"Estriol","bool":false},{"option":"Equine estrogen","bool":false},{"option":"Ethinyl estradiol","bool":true}]},{"id":3,"info":"4th-year/reproductive/2017","question":"What weight is considered a low birth weight of a newborn baby?","answers":[{"option":"4.0-4.5 kg","bool":false},{"option":"3.0-3.5 kg","bool":false},{"option":"<2.5 kg","bool":true},{"option":"2.5-3.0 kg","bool":false},{"option":"3.5-4.0 kg","bool":false}]},{"id":4,"info":"4th-year/reproductive/2017","question":"What is the range for average birth weight in developing countries?","answers":[{"option":"2.0-3.0 kgs","bool":false},{"option":"3.0-4.0 kgs","bool":false},{"option":"2.5-3.5 kgs","bool":true},{"option":"3.5-4.5 kgs","bool":false},{"option":"3.5-3.0 kgs","bool":false}]},{"id":5,"info":"4th-year/reproductive/2017","question":"What is a contraindication for the external cephalic version?","answers":[{"option":"Kneeling breech","bool":false},{"option":"Frank breech","bool":false},{"option":"Oligohydramnios","bool":true},{"option":"Microcephaly","bool":false},{"option":"Anencephaly","bool":false}]},{"id":6,"info":"4th-year/reproductive/2017","question":"Lambda sign is an ultrasound finding of what condition?","answers":[{"option":"Dichorionic diamniotic twin pregnancy","bool":true},{"option":"Dichorionic monoamniotic twin pregnancy","bool":false},{"option":"Trichorionic triamniotic triplet pregnancy","bool":false},{"option":"Monochorionic diamniotic twin pregnancy","bool":false},{"option":"Monochorionic monoamniotic twin pregnancy","bool":false}]},{"id":7,"info":"4th-year/reproductive/2017","question":"What is the overall risk of miscarriage in chorionic villous sampling?","answers":[{"option":"6%","bool":false},{"option":"4%","bool":false},{"option":"8%","bool":false},{"option":"2%","bool":true},{"option":"10%","bool":false}]},{"id":8,"info":"4th-year/reproductive/2017","question":"What is the estimated increase in risk for venous thromboembolism in  pregnant woman as compared to a non-pregnant woman?","answers":[{"option":"Fourfold increase","bool":false},{"option":"Twofold increase","bool":false},{"option":"Threefold increase","bool":false},{"option":"Tenfold increase","bool":true},{"option":"Elevenfold increase","bool":false}]},{"id":9,"info":"4th-year/reproductive/2017","question":"Complete moles can sometimes persist in the uterus or convert into invasive moles. What is the risk percentage of such a complication?","answers":[{"option":"5%","bool":false},{"option":"15%","bool":true},{"option":"20%","bool":false},{"option":"2.5%","bool":false},{"option":"10%","bool":false}]},{"id":10,"info":"4th-year/reproductive/2017","question":"The lower 2/3 of the vagina is derived from which embryological structure?","answers":[{"option":"Mullerian duct","bool":false},{"option":"Wolffian duct","bool":false},{"option":"Urogenital sinus","bool":true},{"option":"Genital tubercle","bool":false},{"option":"Labioscrotal swelling","bool":false}]},{"id":11,"info":"4th-year/reproductive/2017","question":"Primordial germ cells are derived from which embryological structure?","answers":[{"option":"Primary follicle","bool":false},{"option":"Syncytiotrophoblast","bool":false},{"option":"Mesoderm","bool":false},{"option":"Yolk sac","bool":true},{"option":"Neural tube","bool":false}]},{"id":12,"info":"4th-year/reproductive/2017","question":"Following surgical termination of pregnancy, what must be prescribed to the patient?","answers":[{"option":"Aspirin","bool":false},{"option":"Antibiotics","bool":true},{"option":"Metformin","bool":false},{"option":"Combined oral contraceptive (COC) pill","bool":false},{"option":"Corticosteroids","bool":false}]},{"id":13,"info":"4th-year/reproductive/2017","question":"What is the classic abdominal examination finding of abruptio placentae?","answers":[{"option":"Rebound tenderness","bool":false},{"option":"\"Woody hard\" uterus on palpation","bool":true},{"option":"Fluid thrill is positive","bool":false},{"option":"\"Rock hard\" abdomen on palpation","bool":false},{"option":"\"Stony dull\" sounds on percussion","bool":false}]},{"id":14,"info":"4th-year/reproductive/2017","question":"Which heart disease has the highest incidence in pregnant women?","answers":[{"option":"Ventricular septal defect","bool":false},{"option":"Atrial septal defect","bool":false},{"option":"Mitral regurgitation","bool":false},{"option":"Aortic stenosis","bool":false},{"option":"Mitral stenosis","bool":true}]},{"id":15,"info":"4th-year/reproductive/2017","question":"A 24-year-old female G1P0 presents to the emergency room with lower abdominal pain, vaginal discharge, and shoulder pain. The abdominal pain began 2 days ago when she noticed yellowish vaginal discharge with clots of blood in it. She also says that there is a pain in the tip of her right shoulder. What is the most likely diagnosis?","answers":[{"option":"Ectopic pregnancy","bool":true},{"option":"Threatened miscarriage","bool":false},{"option":"Fibroids","bool":false},{"option":"Abruptio placentae","bool":false},{"option":"Molar pregnancy","bool":false}]},{"id":16,"info":"4th-year/reproductive/2017","question":"A 43-year-old woman presented to the gynecology outpatient clinic with complaints of heavy menstrual bleeding. She is post-menopausal and started bleeding a few days ago. Flow is heavy and there are clots of the blood being discharged from the vagina. Ultrasound of pelvis shows thick endometrial stripe with a normal-sized uterus. What investigation would you advise?","answers":[{"option":"CT scan with contrast","bool":false},{"option":"X-ray of the pelvis","bool":false},{"option":"Pap smear","bool":false},{"option":"Hysteroscopy with biopsy","bool":true},{"option":"Hysterosalpingogram","bool":false}]},{"id":17,"info":"4th-year/reproductive/2017","question":"Transient tachypnea of the newborn resolves within how many hours?","answers":[{"option":"24 hours","bool":false},{"option":"72 hours","bool":true},{"option":"12 hours","bool":false},{"option":"48 hours","bool":false},{"option":"36 hours","bool":false}]},{"id":18,"info":"4th-year/reproductive/2017","question":"What is the most common complication in a twin pregnancy?","answers":[{"option":"Preterm delivery","bool":true},{"option":"Venous thromboembolism","bool":false},{"option":"Abruptio placentae","bool":false},{"option":"Uterine rupture","bool":false},{"option":"Pre-eclampsia","bool":false}]},{"id":19,"info":"4th-year/reproductive/2017","question":"Which process is necessary for fertilization to occur?","answers":[{"option":"Sperm-zona pellucida binding","bool":false},{"option":"Acrosome reaction","bool":false},{"option":"Zona pellucida penetration","bool":false},{"option":"Sperm capacitation","bool":true},{"option":"Zona reaction","bool":false}]},{"id":20,"info":"4th-year/reproductive/2017","question":"A 35-year-old woman, known case of diabetes mellitus type 2, delivered a baby boy at 30 weeks of gestation. The newborn requires oxygen support. What is the condition he is most likely suffering from?","answers":[{"option":"Meconium aspiration syndrome","bool":false},{"option":"Pulmonary hypoplasia","bool":false},{"option":"Persistent pulmonary hypertension of the newborn","bool":false},{"option":"Neonatal respiratory distress syndrome","bool":true},{"option":"Transient tachypnea of the newborn","bool":false}]},{"id":21,"info":"4th-year/reproductive/2017","question":"When millennial goals failed what new goals were set?","answers":[{"option":"Sustainable development goals","bool":true},{"option":"Operational short-term goals","bool":false},{"option":"Long-term development goals","bool":false},{"option":"Single-use development goals","bool":false},{"option":"Yearly-use development goals","bool":false}]},{"id":22,"info":"4th-year/reproductive/2017","question":"Which of the following is untrue about the anatomy of the female pelvis?","answers":[{"option":"Wings of the ileum are larger in females","bool":false},{"option":"Pelvic outlet is 13.5 cm in antero-posterior diameter","bool":false},{"option":"Pelvic inlet is 11 cm in antero-posterior diameter","bool":false},{"option":"Pelvic inlet is heart-shaped in females","bool":true},{"option":"Pudendal nerve passes behind and below the ischial spine","bool":false}]},{"id":23,"info":"4th-year/reproductive/2017","question":"What is the most common maternal cause of breech presentation?","answers":[{"option":"Bicornuate uterus","bool":false},{"option":"Placenta previa","bool":false},{"option":"Fibroids","bool":true},{"option":"Septate uterus","bool":false},{"option":"Uterine didelphys","bool":false}]},{"id":24,"info":"4th-year/reproductive/2017","question":"What is the first-line  treatment for menorrhagia?","answers":[{"option":"Tranexamic acid","bool":false},{"option":"GnRH agonists","bool":false},{"option":"Levonorgestrel intrauterine system (LNG-IUS)","bool":true},{"option":"Mefenemic acid","bool":false},{"option":"Combined oral contraceptive pills (COCPs)","bool":false}]},{"id":25,"info":"4th-year/reproductive/2017","question":"A 27-year-old female came with a history of amenorrhea for a month. She has had a miscarriage and her uterus was evacuated. She denies any history of hirsutism, galactorrhea, or dysmenorrhea. She says she has gained weight since the D&C. What is your most likely diagnosis?","answers":[{"option":"Prolactinoma","bool":false},{"option":"Hypothalamic malfunction","bool":false},{"option":"Polycystic ovarian syndrome","bool":false},{"option":"Premature ovarian follicle","bool":false},{"option":"Asherman syndrome","bool":true}]},{"id":26,"info":"4th-year/reproductive/2017","question":"A 19-year-old female presents to the gynecology clinic with complaints of abnormal hair growth and weight gain. She has normal serum insulin levels and her menstrual cycles are regular. What is the treatment of choice for hirsutism in this patient?","answers":[{"option":"Metformin","bool":false},{"option":"Combined oral contraceptive pills","bool":false},{"option":"Clomiphene","bool":false},{"option":"Eflornithine cream","bool":true},{"option":"Cyproterone acetate","bool":false}]},{"id":27,"info":"4th-year/reproductive/2017","question":"A 22-year-old female came to the clinic for a pap smear. Her results showed mild dyskaryosis and dysplasia involving less than 1/3 of the basal membrane. What is the next step in this case?","answers":[{"option":"Colposcopy, cytology after 6 months","bool":true},{"option":"Trachelectomy","bool":false},{"option":"Loop electrosurgical excision procedure (LEEP)","bool":false},{"option":"Hysterectomy","bool":false},{"option":"Large loop excision of transformation zone (LLETZ)","bool":false}]},{"id":28,"info":"4th-year/reproductive/2017","question":"A 29-year-old woman G2P1 29 weeks gestation comes to the emergency room with severe headache and edema. Her blood pressure is 160/100. CNS examination revealed decreased visual acuity and an altered level of consciousness. What is your provisional diagnosis?","answers":[{"option":"Gestational hypertension","bool":false},{"option":"Preeclampsia","bool":true},{"option":"Chronic hypertension","bool":false},{"option":"Eclampsia","bool":false},{"option":"HELLP syndrome","bool":false}]},{"id":29,"info":"4th-year/reproductive/2017","question":"A 24-year-old woman comes to the clinic with complaints of pain at the episiotomy site and fecal discharge from the vagina. She had an assisted vaginal delivery 6 weeks ago. What is your most likely diagnosis?","answers":[{"option":"Rectocele","bool":false},{"option":"Rectal prolapse","bool":false},{"option":"Infection at suture site","bool":false},{"option":"Rectovaginal fistula","bool":true},{"option":"Improper sutures of episiotomy","bool":false}]},{"id":30,"info":"4th-year/reproductive/2017","question":"A 25-year-old female visits the gynecology clinic with complaints of mood swings just before her periods. Her menstrual cycles are regular and she has normal flow. What is the management of this patient's complaint?","answers":[{"option":"Combined oral contraceptive pills","bool":false},{"option":"Transdermal patch","bool":false},{"option":"Primrose oil","bool":true},{"option":"Progestogen-only pills","bool":false},{"option":"Progestogen-only injectable","bool":false}]},{"id":31,"info":"4th-year/reproductive/2017","question":"Endometrial carcinoma type 1 is associated with which of the following conditions?","answers":[{"option":"Endometrial hyperplasia","bool":true},{"option":"Low Body Mass Index","bool":false},{"option":"Overexpression of p16 mutations","bool":false},{"option":"p53 mutation","bool":false},{"option":"Menopause","bool":false}]},{"id":32,"info":"4th-year/reproductive/2017","question":"What would the birthweight be of a baby that has been classified as 'macrosomic'?","answers":[{"option":">4.0 kg","bool":true},{"option":"1-2 kg","bool":false},{"option":"<1.5 kg","bool":false},{"option":"3-4 kg","bool":false},{"option":"2-3 kg","bool":false}]},{"id":33,"info":"4th-year/reproductive/2017","question":"A newborn baby comes to the clinic with complaints of tremors in his hands and feet. What is a likely cause of this?","answers":[{"option":"Epilepsy","bool":false},{"option":"Hyponatremia","bool":false},{"option":"Hypocalcemia","bool":false},{"option":"Hypoglycemia","bool":true},{"option":"Meningitis","bool":false}]},{"id":34,"info":"4th-year/reproductive/2017","question":"What is the treatment of 3rd degree uterovaginal prolapse?","answers":[{"option":"Kegel exercises","bool":false},{"option":"Sacrocolpopexy","bool":false},{"option":"Sacrospinous fixation","bool":false},{"option":"Supportive pessaries","bool":false},{"option":"Sacrohysteropexy","bool":true}]},{"id":35,"info":"4th-year/reproductive/2017","question":"From whom does a child inherit the D antigen?","answers":[{"option":"Father","bool":false},{"option":"Mother","bool":false},{"option":"Mutation","bool":false},{"option":"Parents","bool":true},{"option":"Acquired","bool":false}]},{"id":36,"info":"4th-year/reproductive/2017","question":"A 29-year-old woman G1P0 at 18 weeks gestation presents to the clinic with complaints of grape-like mass discharge from her vagina for the past 8 days. Ultrasound of the pelvis shows snowstorm appearance. What is the diagnosis?","answers":[{"option":"Polyhydramnios","bool":false},{"option":"Teratoma","bool":false},{"option":"Complete mole","bool":true},{"option":"Partial mole","bool":false},{"option":"Choriocarcinoma","bool":false}]},{"id":37,"info":"4th-year/reproductive/2017","question":"A 28-year-old female comes to the clinic at 18 weeks gestation for routine follow-up. Her ultrasound scan shows twin pregnancy. What is a question you would ask her upon noting this finding?","answers":[{"option":"Gravidity","bool":false},{"option":"History of ovarian induction","bool":true},{"option":"Age","bool":false},{"option":"Parity","bool":false},{"option":"Name","bool":false}]},{"id":38,"info":"4th-year/reproductive/2017","question":"Hot flashes, declining bone health, and amenorrhea are all symptoms of menopause. What is the biochemical cause of these symptoms?","answers":[{"option":"Decreased estrogen","bool":true},{"option":"Decreased FSH","bool":false},{"option":"Decreased progesterone","bool":false},{"option":"Decreased LH","bool":false},{"option":"Decreased GnRH","bool":false}]},{"id":39,"info":"4th-year/reproductive/2017","question":"A 29-year-old woman presents to the clinic with complaints of abnormal hair growth and irregular menstrual periods. She has not had her period for 2 months. She has 1 child who is 8 months old. What is the preferred treatment for this patient?","answers":[{"option":"Eflornithine cream","bool":false},{"option":"Combined oral contraceptive pills","bool":true},{"option":"Diet counselling","bool":false},{"option":"Progesterone-only pills","bool":false},{"option":"Metformin","bool":false}]},{"id":40,"info":"4th-year/reproductive/2017","question":"Which of the following best describes birth weight in the 90th percentile?","answers":[{"option":"Above average for gestational age","bool":false},{"option":"Small for gestational age","bool":false},{"option":"Large for gestational age","bool":true},{"option":"Average for gestational age","bool":false},{"option":"Below average for gestational age","bool":false}]},{"id":41,"info":"4th-year/reproductive/2017","question":"A 27-year-old woman G1P0 gestational age of 37+6 presents to the emergency for uterine contractions. She is 7 cm dilated but labor has not progressed since her admission 4 hours ago. Uterine contractions are 5 in 10 minutes. Her ultrasound scans reveal a fetal weight of 4000 g. What is this woman's condition called?","answers":[{"option":"Prolonged labor","bool":false},{"option":"Dysfunction uterine activity","bool":false},{"option":"Secondary arrest of labor","bool":true},{"option":"Delayed labor","bool":false},{"option":"Primary arrest of labor","bool":false}]},{"id":42,"info":"4th-year/reproductive/2017","question":"What is the most likely cause of the poor prognosis of labor?","answers":[{"option":"Large gestational age","bool":false},{"option":"Cephalopelvic disproportion","bool":false},{"option":"Nulliparity","bool":false},{"option":"Insufficient maternal push","bool":false},{"option":"Inefficient uterine contractions","bool":true}]},{"id":43,"info":"4th-year/reproductive/2017","question":"What is considered a small gestational age?","answers":[{"option":"<10th percentile","bool":true},{"option":"20th-30th percentile","bool":false},{"option":"10th-20th percentile","bool":false},{"option":"<5th percentile","bool":false},{"option":"30th-40th percentile","bool":false}]},{"id":44,"info":"4th-year/reproductive/2017","question":"What is the minimum gestational age for a term infant?","answers":[{"option":"37 weeks","bool":true},{"option":"22 weeks","bool":false},{"option":"27 weeks","bool":false},{"option":"36 weeks","bool":false},{"option":"34 weeks","bool":false}]},{"id":45,"info":"4th-year/reproductive/2017","question":"What is the gold standard investigation for endometriosis?","answers":[{"option":"Transvaginal ultrasound","bool":false},{"option":"Pap smear","bool":false},{"option":"Laproscopy","bool":true},{"option":"Hysterosalpingogram","bool":false},{"option":"Ultrasound pelvis","bool":false}]},{"id":46,"info":"4th-year/reproductive/2017","question":"A 27-year-old female comes to the clinic with complaints of severe pain in menstruation. She complains that her uterus feels like it is squeezing itself every time she has her menstrual cycle and that it is very painful. Upon per vaginal examination, a nodular mass is palpated near the pouch of Douglas. What is your most likely diagnosis?","answers":[{"option":"Ovarian hemorrhagic cyst","bool":false},{"option":"Endometriosis","bool":true},{"option":"Ovarian torsion","bool":false},{"option":"Uterine leiomyoma","bool":false},{"option":"Cervical cancer","bool":false}]},{"id":47,"info":"4th-year/reproductive/2017","question":"What is the most common cause of vesicovaginal fistula in Pakistan?","answers":[{"option":"Weak muscular walls due to malnutrition","bool":false},{"option":"Manual delivery of placenta","bool":false},{"option":"Injury to bladder during pelvic surgery","bool":true},{"option":"Human papillomavirus","bool":false},{"option":"Cephalopelvic disproportion","bool":false}]},{"id":48,"info":"4th-year/reproductive/2017","question":"Which of the following is a complication of fetal growth retardation?","answers":[{"option":"Hyperthermia","bool":false},{"option":"Sepsis","bool":false},{"option":"Hyperglycemia","bool":false},{"option":"Anemia","bool":false},{"option":"Polycythemia","bool":true}]},{"id":49,"info":"4th-year/reproductive/2017","question":"What is not a factor in causing a vesicovaginal fistula?","answers":[{"option":"Malignancy","bool":false},{"option":"Prolonged labor","bool":false},{"option":"Obstructed labor","bool":false},{"option":"Smoking","bool":true},{"option":"Radiotherapy","bool":false}]},{"id":50,"info":"4th-year/reproductive/2017","question":"A 25-year-old female presents to the clinic with complaints of urinary incontinence for 2 days. She had an emergency C-section 12 days ago after prolonged labor. What is your diagnosis of this woman?","answers":[{"option":"Vesicovaginal fistula","bool":true},{"option":"Urethral hypermobility","bool":false},{"option":"Detrusor sphincter dyssynergia","bool":false},{"option":"Urinary tract infection","bool":false},{"option":"Intrinsic sphincter deficiency","bool":false}]},{"id":51,"info":"4th-year/reproductive/2017","question":"A 25-year-old female presents to the clinic with complaints of urinary incontinence for 2 days. She had an emergency cesarean section 12 days ago after prolonged labor. What is your treatment for this woman?","answers":[{"option":"Fulguration","bool":false},{"option":"Surgical correction","bool":false},{"option":"Kegel exercises","bool":false},{"option":"Sympathomimetics prescribed","bool":false},{"option":"Foley's catheter placed for 12 days","bool":true}]},{"id":52,"info":"4th-year/reproductive/2017","question":"How is a high-risk preterm delivery managed?","answers":[{"option":"Antibiotic prophylaxis","bool":false},{"option":"Terbutaline","bool":false},{"option":"Tocolytics","bool":false},{"option":"Bed rest","bool":false},{"option":"Steroids","bool":true}]},{"id":53,"info":"4th-year/reproductive/2017","question":"A 30-year-old female presents to the clinic with abdominal distension for 4 days. She is a known case of mucinous cystadenoma. What investigation would you advise?","answers":[{"option":"Hystersalpingogram","bool":false},{"option":"CT scan","bool":true},{"option":"Magnetic resonance imaging (MRI)","bool":false},{"option":"Transvaginal ultrasound","bool":false},{"option":"Ultrasound","bool":false}]},{"id":54,"info":"4th-year/reproductive/2017","question":"What is the best time to check fibronectin levels?","answers":[{"option":"37-40 weeks","bool":false},{"option":"18-22 weeks","bool":false},{"option":"14-18 weeks","bool":false},{"option":"22-36 weeks","bool":true},{"option":"10-14 weeks","bool":false}]},{"id":55,"info":"4th-year/reproductive/2017","question":"A woman has gestational diabetes mellitus (GDM) screening for type 2 diabetes mellitus with HbA1c levels is done how long after delivery?","answers":[{"option":"48 hours postpartum","bool":false},{"option":"2-6 weeks after childbirth","bool":false},{"option":"10 days postpartum","bool":false},{"option":"24 hours postpartum","bool":false},{"option":"6-13 weeks after birth","bool":true}]},{"id":56,"info":"4th-year/reproductive/2017","question":"A nulliparous woman comes to the clinic with pain all throughout her menses. The uterus is retroverted on ultrasound. What investigation is indicated in this woman for diagnosis?","answers":[{"option":"CT scan","bool":false},{"option":"Laproscopy","bool":true},{"option":"MRI","bool":false},{"option":"Transvaginal ultrasound","bool":false},{"option":"Hysterosalpingography","bool":false}]},{"id":57,"info":"4th-year/reproductive/2017","question":"Which of the following is not associated with mammary gland ectasia?","answers":[{"option":"Trauma","bool":false},{"option":"Obesity","bool":false},{"option":"Family history","bool":false},{"option":"Smoking","bool":true},{"option":"Age","bool":false}]},{"id":58,"info":"4th-year/reproductive/2017","question":"What is the most debilitating complication expected in a neonate who is untreated with serum bilirubin 22 mg/dl and indirect 18 mg/dl on 1st day of life?","answers":[{"option":"Birth asphyxia","bool":false},{"option":"Anemia","bool":false},{"option":"Hypocalcemia","bool":false},{"option":"Kernicterus","bool":true},{"option":"Hypoglycemia","bool":false}]}]
export default arr